trupanion.com 2016-11-20

# Privacy Policy - Trupanion

Trupanion understands the importance of your privacy and security, especially when making purchases online.

##### Trupanion, a pet insurance provider you can count on!

**Better Business Bureau Accreditation**

Trupanion understands the importance of your privacy and security, especially when making purchases online. Trupanion has been a [Better Business Bureau Accredited](https://www.bbb.org/western-washington/business-reviews/insurance-companies/trupanion-in-seattle-wa-22429232) company since December 2002, and has a **BBB Rating of A+ (2014)**  (the highest rating BBB offers). 

**Verisign Secure Site Program**

Trupanion’s website also undergoes daily website security tests through **Verisign Secure Site Program** , an identity and authentication security service. We want to make sure that your information is protected and that you are given the reassurance that you can safely purchase through our website.

### Trupanion privacy policy

Effective February 19, 2016

IMPORTANT PRIVACY NOTICE REGARDING YOUR NONPUBLIC PERSONAL INFORMATION:

At Trupanion and American Pet Insurance Company, we know the importance of respecting your privacy and maintaining your trust. We have physical, electronic, and procedural security measures in place that comply with legal standards to protect your personal information.

**

_(1) What we collect_

**

In order for us to obtain or service the insurance products that you ask for from us, we may collect personal information from you, as well as from others. Personal information includes any identifying information, such as:

  * Your name, address, email address, and phone number

  * Your age, marital status, occupation, social security number, assets, income, and beneficiaries

  * Your credit history, credit standing, policy coverage, claim history, premiums, and payment history

We may collect your personal information from:

  * You in person, by telephone, or over the internet

  * Forms submitted to us by you or on your behalf, such as applications, claims, and policy updates

  * Your business dealings with us and with other companies

  * Consumer reporting agencies

  * Veterinarians

**

_(2) How we use personal information_

**

We do not sell your personal information to anyone, for any reason. We only disclose your personal information, as allowed by this privacy policy or required by law. In those specific instances, we may disclose your personal information without your prior consent.

In order for us to obtain or to service the insurance products that you ask for from us, we may need to disclose your information to our affiliates and to certain third parties.

Our affiliates includes insurance companies, insurance agencies, and other financial service companies: (1) that we own or control; (2) that own or control us; (3) that are owned or controlled by the same company that owns and controls us; and/or (4) that own or control the same company that owns and controls us.

We also may disclose personal information to one or more of the following unaffiliated third parties:

  * Financial companies, such as life, automobile, and property insurers, and insurance agents or brokers

  * Our service providers and business partners, which may help process or service your account

  * Veterinary facilities or providers

  * A court, governmental, or regulatory agency when there is a lawful request

  * Law enforcement when there is a lawful request, including to protect against fraud or unauthorized transactions

  * A group policyholder for purposes of billing and collecting premium and/or reporting claims experience

  * Any service providers that perform insurance and/or business functions for us

  * Any business partners that provide services and/or fulfillment on behalf of us

We may share personal information with insurance data banks that collect information about claim history, accident fault, and amounts paid. Insurance data banks may retain that information and disclose it to other insurance companies and other third parties legally entitled to see it.

We send our members a privacy notice each year. If our practices change in a material way, we will inform you promptly. We treat our former members’ information with the same level of protection as our current members’ information.

**

_(3) Your right to access_

**

You have the right to access and request the correction, amendment, or deletion of all of your recorded personal information that has been collected by us. If you wish to review your recorded personal information, please [contact us](http://trupanion.com/about/contact). Please include your name, address, telephone number, and policy number, and let us know what kind of information you want to see. You may see and copy your information in person, or if you prefer, we will copy and send you your information. If you see any mistakes, please let us know and we will review it. If we agree, we will correct our files. If we disagree, you may file a short statement of dispute with us. Your statement will be included with any data we disclose in the future. We will also send the statement to anyone you ask us to who received your information from us in the past two years.

**

_(4) Regarding Trupanion.com_

**

We also want to make you aware of how we use online data collecting devices known as "cookies." Many commercial Internet websites use "cookies." "Cookies" are files we place in your computer's browser to store your preferences relating to our website. If you disable "cookies" on your browser, the website will not remember your preferences, and you will not be able to access a customized default home page view of our website. Our "cookies" are only used when you are visiting our website. While a code in the "cookie" file enables the website to label you as a particular user, "cookies" by themselves do not tell us your email address or other personally identifiable information. Only you can provide that information on our website — if you expressly choose to do so or if the preferences in your browser choose to do so automatically, in which case it may identify you by name, address, or other personal information.

"Cookies" help us understand your website usage so we can continually improve its usability. For example, if you have enabled this option, we may use "cookies" to personalize your experience on our website (e.g., to remember your customer ID on a login page). We may also use "cookies" to offer you other insurance and financial services products that may suit your needs. During the period you are logged into our website, we log Internet Protocol (IP) addresses (a number assigned to your computer when you use the Internet), browser and platform types, domain name, access times, referral data (the last website address or Uniform Resource Locator (URL) you visited before logging into our website and the first website address or URL you visit after leaving our website), and your activity while using our website.

While you may choose to disable cookies via your browser settings, doing so may not allow us to enhance your web user experience. Non-personally identifiable information may be collected, which may be used in Google Analytics features, such as demographics and interest reporting, remarketing, display network impression reporting, and DoubleClick campaign manager integration. Visitors can opt-out of Google Analytics for display advertising and customize Google display network ads by visiting Google Ads settings.

We use the SSL protocol, secure servers, and security protocol to safeguard the information you submit over the internet. It is important to note that email messages are not secure. Email messages traveling through the internet are subject to viewing, alteration, and copying by potentially anyone on the internet.

This website contains links to other websites. We provide links to other websites as a convenience to persons who visit our website. If you choose to use the services provided by those websites, you may be asked by those websites to provide certain personally identifiable information. Please be aware that we are not responsible for the privacy practices of those websites, even if our name or logo appear on those websites. Please be aware that when you leave our website, we encourage you to read the privacy policies of each and every website that you visit, as the privacy policies of those websites may differ from ours. This privacy statement applies solely to this website.

We also work with a number of third-party internet advertising companies to serve behaviorally-targeted advertising to a variety of our website visitors. You may choose to opt out from participating in behavioral targeted advertising by visiting the Network Advertising Initiative (NAI) opt out page: <http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp>.

By opting out, you will stop receiving behavioral target ads from your visits to this website, but this does not mean you will be served any non-behavioral ads, nor does opting out stop information from being collected.

**

_(5) Questions?_

**

Please feel free to [contact us](http://trupanion.com/about/contact) if you would like to ask us any questions about our privacy policy or anything else.
